Guide to the Department of History Records, 1932-[ongoing] UA.25.23.0001
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Administrative Files, 1932-1985, 22 boxes
  - Office of the Chair, 1951-1985
    - Work Study, 1974 (Box 17)
    - Academic Council-Report on Athletics, 1969 (Box 17)
    - Ad-hoc Graduate Placement Committee, 1963 (Box 17)
    - Active Administrative-tenure, 1968 (Box 17)
    - Africa Search, 1966-1970, 2 folders (Box 17)
    - African Studies Program, 1966 (Box 17)
    - African-American History-recruiting, 1968-1969 (Box 17)
    - American Association of University Professors, 1968-1972 (Box 17)
    - American Council on Education-Report, 1969, 1971 (Box 17)
    - AHA-departmental, 1961-1965 (Box 17)
    - AHA-History Education Project, 1969 (Box 17)
    - AHA-miscellaneous, 1966-1967 (Box 17)
    - Appointments-Commonwealth possibilities, 1959-1960 (Box 17)
    - Barchas Collection, 1974-1975 (Box 17)
    - Bicentennial, North Carolina, 1973 (Box 17)
    - Black Studies Department, 1975-1980 (Box 17)
    - Boyd Professorship, 1961-1963 (Box 17)
    - Budget
      - News, undated (Box 17)
      - Budget and Recommendations, 1952 (Box 17)
      - 1953 July (Box 17)
      - 1955-1958 (Box 17)
      - Budget Recommendations, 1958-1959 (Box 17)
      - 1958-1959 (Box 17)
      - Budget Recommendations, 1960-1961 (Box 17)
      - Budget Requests, 1961-1962 (Box 17)
      - Actual, 1960-1969, 9 folders (Box 17)
      - Additional items, 1967-1970 (Box 17)
      - Additional items-ACLS, 1967-1970 (Box 17)
      - Budget Recommendations, 1962-1963 (Box 17)
      - Budget Requests, 1963-1969, 6 folders (Box 17)
      - Budget Proposals, 1967-1970, 2 folders (Box 17)
      - Approved, 1971-1972 (Box 17)
    - Bulletin and Committee on Honors, 1963-1966 (Box 17)
    - By-Laws, departmental discussion and adoption, 1969-1970 (Box 17)
    - By-Laws, Colton proposals and reaction, 1970 (Box 17)
    - By-Laws, 1970 (Box 17)
    - Calkins, Prof. Phillip B., 1973, undated (Box 17)
    - Census Reports (7 Folders), 1968 fall-1971 fall (Box 17)
    - Center for Southern Historical Studies, 1970 (Box 17)
    - Center for Southern Studies, undated (Box 17)
    - Chairman and Director of Undergraduate Studies, 1972-1973 (Box 18)
    - "Chronicle" episode, 1969 Feb.-March (Box 18)
    - Class Rolls, History 191-194, 1969-1970 (Box 18)
    - Class Rolls, History 399, 1969-1970 (Box 18)
    - Classical Studies-proposals, 1966, undated (Box 18)
    - Committee on the Comparative Study of Social Institutions and Systems (2 Folders), 1964-1970 (Box 18)
    - Committee on International Studies, 1967, 1970 (Box 18)
    - Committee on Russian Studies and Cooperative Program in Russian and East European Studies, 1967-1971 (Box 18)
    - Committee on Public Education and the Training of Teachers, 1967-1969 (Box 18)
    - Commonwealth, 1963-1964 (Box 18)
    - Comparative Area Studies Major: Africa, Asia, and Latin America, 1973, undated (Box 18)
    - Computation Center, 1967 (Box 18)
    - Computer Arrangements, 1969-1973 (Box 18)
    - Computer Science Program, 1970-1971 (Box 18)
    - Consultant Services, department and University, 1967-1968 (Box 18)
    - Cooperative Program in East Asia Studies, 1968-1969 (Box 18)
    - Cooperative Program Fellows, 1968-1969 (Box 18)
    - Cooperative Program in the Humanities, 1967 (Box 18)
    - Cooperative Program in International Studies, 1967 (Box 18)
    - Correspondence, 1968-1973, 10 folders (Box 18)
    - Correspondence-miscellaneous, 1970 summer, 1972, 2 folders (Box 18)
    - Correspondence, Memoranda and Routine Announcements, 1973-1974 (Box 18)
    - Correspondence with Prof. Richard Watson, 1971 Jan.-July (Box 18)
    - Courses-advanced placement, 1965 (Box 18)
    - Courses-Committee approval, 1960-1966 (Box 18)
    - Course Approval, 1981 (Box 18)
    - Course Instructor Approval-Graduate Courses (2 Folders), 1960-1967 (Box 18)
    - Course Approval-Graduate Courses, 1961-1972 (Box 19)
    - Course Approval-Undergraduate (2 Folders), 1965-1981 (Box 19)
    - Courses dropped, 1971-1973 (Box 19)
    - Courses retired, 1966-1973 (Box 19)
    - Courses-miscellaneous, 1976-1980, 3 folders (Box 19)
    - Curriculum-new, 1968-1969 (Box 19)
    - Curtiss/Woody/Manchester/Nelson retirement, 1959-1972 (Box 19)
    - Danforth Foundation, 1967-1970 (Box 19)
    - Dear Colleague, 1981-1982 (Box 19)
    - Department, Long-Range Planning, 1964-1965 (Box 19)
    - Department, old schedules, 1964-1974, 3 folders (Box 19)
    - Department, old course schedules, 1971-1972 (Box 19)
    - Departmental Bulletins, 1972 Sept.-1973 April (Box 19)
    - Departmental Meetings, 1966-1971, 2 folders (Box 19)
    - Departmental Meetings, minutes, 1971-1977 (Box 19)
    - Departmental Memoranda and Routine Correspondence (2 Folders), 1969 June-1971 July (Box 19)
    - Departmental Miscellaneous, 1967-1969 (Box 19)
    - Departmental Planning Committee, 1967, 2 folders (Box 19)
    - Director of Graduate and Undergraduate Studies, nominations, 1970 July (Box 19)
    - Director of Graduate Studies, replacement, 1969-1971 (Box 19)
    - Duke Summer Abroad Program, 1966 (Box 19)
    - Duke University in the news, 1966 (Box 19)
    - Duke University Symposium, 1963 March (Box 19)
    - Economic Opportunities Act, 1967 (Box 19)
    - Educational Administration Advisory Group, 1969-1971 (Box 19)
    - Entertainment Fund, 1969-1970 (Box 19)
    - Epoch Campaign and Faculty Scholarship Fund, 1973 (Box 19)
    - Equipment Information, 1981 (Box 20)
    - European History Newsletter, 1965-1974 (Box 20)
    - European Studies Center, 1971-1972 (Box 20)
    - Executive Committee, 1964-1974 Aug., 11 folders (Box 20)
    - Executive Committee election, 1974 April (Box 20)
    - Faculty Club, 1966-1968 (Box 20)
    - Faculty Newsletter, 1966-1968 (Box 20)
    - Fellowships and Stipends, 1973-1975 (Box 20)
    - Free Academic Senate, 1969 Feb. (Box 20)
    - Full Professors Meeting, 1969 Nov. (Box 20)
    - General Memos-administrative, 1970-1974 (Box 20)
    - Governance Report, 1970-1971 (Box 20)
    - Graduate Rewards, current, 1970-1972 (Box 20)
    - Graduate Course-Social Science Methodology, 1967, undated (Box 20)
    - Graduate Staff Meeting, 1971 (Box 20)
    - Graduate Process-older, 1970-1973 (Box 20)
    - Graduate Requirements and Planning, 1964-1969 (Box 20)
    - Graduate School, 1962 (Box 20)
    - Graduate School: Faculty Meetings and Memoranda, 1971 May-1974 May, 3 folders (Box 20)
    - Graduate Students: rosters and placement, 1969-1973 (Box 20)
    - History 1-2 Reorganization, 1967 Nov.-1968 Sept. (Box 20)
    - History 61-62: Intro to Non-Western Civilization, 1967 (Box 20)
    - History 93: History of Engineering and Proposed NROTC Program, 1967 (Box 20)
    - Hollyday, Prof. Frederic B.M.-correspondence, 1974-1976 (Box 20)
    - History Reading Room, Perkins Library, 1973 (Box 20)
    - Honors Committee, 1965-1967 (Box 20)
    - Honors Program-history, 1967-1981 (Box 21)
    - Humanities Cooperative, 1963-1967, 2 folders (Box 21)
    - Institute/Center of Education, 1977 (Box 21)
    - Interdisciplinary Humanities Course, 1967-1968 (Box 21)
    - Interdisciplinary Program for Majors, 1967-1969 (Box 21)
    - Invoices, 1982, 2 folders (Box 21)
    - Japanese Chinese Language Proposal, 1967 (Box 21)
    - Joerg, Dean Frederick, 1974-1978 (Box 21)
    - Kiwanuka, Matia, 1973 (Box 21)
    - Lewis, Dean Harold, 1962-1971 (Box 21)
    - Libraries-Duke University, 1968-1969 (Box 21)
    - M-Miscellaneous, 1961-1967 (Box 21)
    - March 17, 1972 Meeting (Tenured Faculty), 1972 (Box 21)
    - Mc-Miscellaneous, 1959-1964 (Box 21)
    - Michigan State Salary Report, 1970 (Box 21)
    - Military History-Summer Program, 1967 (Box 21)
    - N-Miscellaneous, 1960-1967 (Box 21)
    - National Defense Education Act (NDEA)-Summer Institute, 1965-1967 (Box 21)
    - NDEA-Summer Institute, bulletins, 1965-1969 (Box 21)
    - Newsletter, 1965-1974 (Box 21)
    - Offices, 1965-1974 (Box 21)
    - Pan-American Institute, 1961 (Box 21)
    - Conference on French History in Honor of Harold Parker, 1976-1977 (Box 21)
    - Parliamentary Papers, citation of, undated (Box 21)
    - Phi Alpha Theta, 1967-1968 (Box 21)
    - Placement-correspondence, 1967-1969 Aug. (Box 21)
    - Placement File, 1971-1972 (Box 21)
    - Planning, 1967-1975, 7 folders (Box 21)
    - Planning Committee Report, 1974 (Box 21)
    - Projects and Programs, support, 1966-1967 (Box 21)
    - Promotions, 1967 fall (Box 21)
    - Promotions, Full Professors Meeting, 1968 fall (Box 21)
    - Promotion Meeting, 1970 Nov. 21 (Box 21)
    - Promotion Meeting, Full and Associate Professors, 1971 Dec. 3 and 1972 Nov. 3, 2 folders (Box 21)
    - Provost's Report, 1968 June 1 (Box 21)
    - R-Miscellaneous, 1959-1966 (Box 21)
    - Readerships, 1966-1970, 1973-1974, 4 folders (Box 21)
    - Registration, changes, 1972-1973 (Box 21)
    - Renaissance Search, 1970 (Box 21)
    - ROTC, 1960 (Box 21)
    - Russian History Search, 1968-1969 (Box 21)
    - Russian History, candidates, 1969 (Box 21)
    - Sabbatical Leaves, 1962-1971 (Box 21)
    - Search, Director of Afro-American Studies, 1970 (Box 21)
    - Search, Social Sciences and Chinese History, 1970-1971 (Box 21)
    - Secretaries, 1961-1965 (Box 21)
    - Secretaries, 1966-1974, 2 folders (Box 22)
    - Seminar Room, 1963-1965 (Box 22)
    - Senior Honors Seminar, 1962, 1966-1967 (Box 22)
    - Social Sciences Council, 1964-1968, 6 folders (Box 22)
    - Social Sciences Council, minutes and associated material, 1964-1965 (Box 22)
    - Social Sciences Program, proposal, 1971 (Box 22)
    - Social Sciences Seminar, 1965 (Box 22)
    - Social Studies Conference, 1962-1963, 2 folders (Box 22)
    - Social Studies Conferences-Education Department, 1967 (Box 22)
    - Social Studies Teachers List, 1960-1961 (Box 22)
    - South Asia, 1962-1965 (Box 22)
    - South Asia, recruiting, 1967 (Box 22)
    - Southern Association of Colleges and Schools, report, 1965 (Box 22)
    - Southern Historical Association (SHA), 1961-1965 (Box 22)
    - SHA-European History Newsletter, 1969 spring (Box 22)
    - Speech to History Majors, 1969 (Box 22)
    - Statistics Courses-Duke University, undated (Box 22)
    - Student correspondence, miscellaneous, 1962-1963 (Box 22)
    - Student Evaluations, 1971-1972, 2 folders (Box 22)
    - Summer Institute, Afro-American History, 1969 (Box 22)
    - Summer Session, 1965-1977, 15 folders (Box 22)
    - Teacher-Course Evaluations, 1966, 1972-1974 spring, 6 folders (Box 22)
    - Technical Report-NDEA Institute, 1966 (Box 22)
    - Tenure, discussions, 1968-1969, 1974 (Box 22)
    - Tenured Faculty Meeting, 1973 April 20 (Box 22)
    - Trinity College Historical Society, 1960-1969, 2 folders (Box 22)
    - Trinity College Historical Society, 1970-1973 (Box 23)
    - Tutorials, 1965-1966 (Box 23)
    - Uhalley, Prof. Stephen, one year replacement, 1970-1971 (Box 23)
    - Undergraduates, minimum uniform requirements, 1969 (Box 23)
    - Undergraduate Assistants, 1969-1970 (Box 23)
    - Undergraduate Education-Report of the Educational Goals Committee, 1964 (Box 23)
    - Undergraduate Faculty Council (UFC)-African-American Studies and Interdisciplinary, 1969 (Box 23)
    - UFC-Small Group Experience, 1971 (Box 23)
    - Undergraduate Studies, 1970-1971 (Box 23)
    - U.S. Government, H.R. 6237, 1963, 1965 (Box 23)
    - U.S. Government, Experienced Teacher Fellowship, 1966-1967 (Box 23)
    - University-Pickets and Protests Policy, 1968 (Box 23)
    - University By-Laws, 1960 (Box 23)
    - University Faculty, 1970 Sept. (Box 23)
    - Visiting Professors, 1961-1965 (Box 23)
    - Varieties of Learning Experience, report, 1968 (Box 23)
    - White, Richard, subcommittee, 1972 (Box 23)
    - Woodrow Wilson Fellowship-nominees, 1967 (Box 23)
    - Budget
      - Approved Budget, 1970-1974, 3 folders (Box 23)
      - Miscellaneous data, 1971 (Box 23)
      - Proposed, 1971 (Box 23)
      - Report on expenditures, 1973-1974 (Box 23)
      - Budget (note for), 1970-1971 (Box 23)
      - Worksheets, 1973-1974 (Box 23)
      - Current expenditures, 1972-1973 (Box 23)
      - Proposed Budget, 1970-1971 (Box 23)
      - Proposed Budget-non-academic, 1971 (Box 23)
      - Proposed Budget, 1972-1973 (Box 23)
      - Proposed Budget-academic, 1973-1974 (Box 23)
    - Alumni and Staff Giving, 1978-1982 (Box 23)
    - Barber Report and response, 1979-1980 (Box 23)
    - Bassett Affair-75th Anniversary, 1977-1979 (Box 23)
    - Boyd Chair, 1978-1979 (Box 23)
    - By-Laws-department, 1978-1981 (Box 23)
    - Canadian Studies, 1975-1981 (Box 23)
    - Departmental Meetings, 1980-1984, 2 folders (Box 23)
    - East Asian Studies, 1981 (Box 23)
    - Executive Committee, 1981-1985, 3 folders (Box 23)
    - Fund Raising, Dr. Anne Scott, 1982-1985 (Box 23)
    - Graduate Program, 1981-1985 (Box 23)
    - Honorary Degrees, 1977-1985 (Box 23)
    - Honors Program, 1983-1985 (Box 23)
    - House Courses, 1974-1984, 2 folders (Box 23)
    - Japanese Search, 1984 (Box 23)
    - JD/MA History, 1983-1984 (Box 23)
    - Leaves, 1981-1985 (Box 23)
    - Legal History, 1984 (Box 23)
    - Mellon Fellowship and Grant, 1976-1981 (Box 23)
    - Named Instructorship, 1981 (Box 23)
    - Nathans, Elizabeth, 1981 (Box 24)
    - Neil Williams, 1983 (Box 24)
    - Office and Classrooms (George Williams), 1980-1985 (Box 24)
    - Organization of American Historians, 1977-1980 (Box 24)
    - Provost, 1979-1984 (Box 24)
  - Director of Graduate Studies, 1932-1983, bulk 1949-1983
    This subseries contains material created and accumulated by the History Department's Director of Graduate Studies. Material present includes correspondence and intra-office memoranda concerning graduate applicants and admissions; awards, fellowships, and grants; assistantships and readerships; graduate courses and requirements; job openings; and communications with the Graduate School. Prominent subjects include Danforth Foundation, National Defense Education Act Fellowship, Master of Arts in Teaching, Cooperative Program in the Humanities, and admitted students affected by the Selective Service (draft). Among the Directors included in the subseries are William T. Laprade, Robert H. Woody, Robert F. Durden, Charles R. Young, and Anne F. Scott.
    - Abbot, William W., III, 1949-1959 (Box 25)
    - Abshire, Charles W., 1951-1952 (Box 25)
    - Adams, William A., 1952 (Box 25)
    - Addy, George M., 1950-1954 (Box 25)
    - Allen, William F., 1949-1950 (Box 25)
    - Berry, Richard S., 1947-1951 (Box 25)
    - Battle, Philip D., 1954-1956 (Box 25)
    - Beers, Burton F., 1950-1955 (Box 25)
    - Bertram, Orion M., 1950-1951 (Box 25)
    - Bell, John B., 1953-1958 (Box 25)
    - Blakely, Florence E., undated (Box 25)
    - Blossom, Thomas, 1948-1952, 1956-1957 (Box 25)
    - Brandon, Barbara, 1953-1958 (Box 25)
    - Bullock, Thomas K., 1954 (Box 25)
    - Casimes, Mary Ann, 1951-1952 (Box 25)
    - Cone, Pauline E., 1949 (Box 25)
    - Cunningham, Noble E., 1953, 1959 (Box 25)
    - Daniel, Wilbon H., 1955-1957 (Box 25)
    - Davis, Marie, undated (Box 25)
    - Davis, Paul I., 1952 (Box 25)
    - Davis, Rodney O., 1949-1953 (Box 25)
    - Dooley, Harold R., 1941, 1951 (Box 25)
    - Erwin, William R., 1960 (Box 25)
    - Esthus, Raymond A., 1949-1956 (Box 25)
    - Evans, Marvin D., 1949 (Box 25)
    - Felt, Jeremy P., 1955 (Box 25)
    - Ferguson, Clyde R., 1955-1960 (Box 25)
    - Gardner, Bonnie Jo, 1955 (Box 25)
    - Gatewood, Willard B., 1953-1956, 1959 (Box 25)
    - Gescher, Dieter, 1951-1953 (Box 25)
    - Gettys, Joseph L., 1949 (Box 25)
    - Grey, Robert C., 1951-1953 (Box 25)
    - Greene, Jack P., 1955-1956 (Box 25)
    - Hall, Leslie M., undated (Box 25)
    - Hamilton, Thomas T., 1947-1950, 1955-1956 (Box 25)
    - Harris, Robert L., 1946-1956 (Box 25)
    - Harrington, William G., 1953-1955 (Box 25)
    - Harvin, Harry L., 1949-1956 (Box 25)
    - Hess, Ursula E., 1953-1955 (Box 25)
    - Higginbotham, Robert D., 1955-1958 (Box 25)
    - Hipps, Jackson S., 1952 (Box 25)
    - Hollyday, Frederick B.M., 1949-1955 (Box 25)
    - Johnson, Allen S., 1951-1958 (Box 25)
    - Jones, Edward L., 1947-1950 (Box 25)
    - Jones, Ruth E., 1951, 1955 (Box 25)
    - Jones, Wayland H., undated (Box 25)
    - Kandlbinder, Hans K., 1953 (Box 25)
    - Karmazin, Michael L., 1951-1952 (Box 25)
    - Leahy, Joseph P., 1952-1956 (Box 25)
    - Lehman, Lowell W., 1953-1955 (Box 25)
    - Leith, James A., 1953 (Box 25)
    - Lewis, J. Claybrook, 1951 (Box 25)
    - Luvaas, Morten J., 1949-1954, 1958 (Box 25)
    - MacLean, Guy R., 1955-1958 (Box 25)
    - MacLean, Robert A. and miscellaneous, 1952-1953 (Box 25)
    - Matthews, Roy T., 1954-1956, 1960 (Box 25)
    - Martin, Roland T., 1957 (Box 25)
    - Middleton, Robert M., 1956 (Box 25)
    - Mitchell, Robert A., 1955 (Box 25)
    - Moffett, William A., 1955 (Box 25)
    - Morse, Theodore T., 1953 (Box 25)
    - Murray, John A., 1952-1957 (Box 25)
    - Noggle, Burl L., 1950-1955, 1958 (Box 25)
    - Norris, Marjorie M., 1951-1952 (Box 25)
    - Oliver, John W., 1953-1956 (Box 25)
    - Oliver, John B., 1948-1952, 1955 (Box 25)
    - Padden, Robert C., 1952 (Box 25)
    - Pierson, Patricia J., 1956, 1958-1959 (Box 25)
    - Pritchard, Howard O., 1949 (Box 25)
    - Ramsey, Robert W., 1955 (Box 25)
    - Ramsaur, Edward G., 1951-1952 (Box 25)
    - Raup, William W., 1948-1952 (Box 25)
    - Rock, William R., 1951-1959 (Box 25)
    - Roth, Russell D., 1951 (Box 25)
    - Russell, Mattie, 1947-1951, 1956 (Box 25)
    - Schoenzeit, Sandra S., 1952 (Box 25)
    - Schultz, Harold J., 1957-1959 (Box 25)
    - Sperry, William H., 1950 (Box 25)
    - Steele, Arthur R., 1949-1957 (Box 25)
    - Stockdale, Harry F., undated (Box 25)
    - Stockton, Manley S., 1952-1954 (Box 25)
    - Sykes, Richard L., 1954 (Box 25)
    - Taylor, Orville W., 1949-1950, 1955-1956 (Box 25)
    - Thoet, Adrienne C., undated (Box 25)
    - Thomas, Theodore H., 1952 (Box 25)
    - Thornburgh, Conway D., 1951 (Box 25)
    - Trent, Mary B., 1951 (Box 25)
    - Tubbesing, James H., 1952-1953 (Box 25)
    - Tyler, Geroge T., 1955 (Box 25)
    - Upton, Anthony F., 1953 (Box 25)
    - Weaver, Fred H., 1953-1954 (Box 25)
    - Webb, John M., 1954 (Box 25)
    - Webster, Rona B., undated (Box 25)
    - Whitcombe, David N., 1951-1953 (Box 25)
    - Williamson, Mary C., undated (Box 25)
    - Yonker, Thomas W., 1954 (Box 25)
    - Ziring, Stanley, 1952-1954 (Box 25)
    - Admissions and Awards, 1966 spring (Box 25)
    - Admissions, 1967 (Box 25)
    - Admissions, 1969 (Box 25)
    - Admissions Applicants, 1962-1963 (Box 25)
    - American Historical Association, 1968 (Box 25)
    - Announcements-grants, scholarships, etc., 1967-1969 (Box 25)
    - Applicants for 1962, 1961 (Box 25)
    - Applicants-awards and admissions, 1969 (Box 25)
    - Applicants-graduate, 1967-1968 (Box 25)
    - Applications for approval of courses, 1957-1958 (Box 25)
    - Appointments Office, 1966 (Box 25)
    - Army Graduate Students, 1967-1969 (Box 25)
    - Award Meetings, 1964-1966 (Box 25)
    - Awards, 1958-1961, 1971-1972, 4 folders (Box 25)
    - Awards-enrolled students, 1968-1969, 2 folders (Box 25)
    - Awards-incoming students, 1968 (Box 25)
    - Awards-new students, 1970-1971 (Box 25)
    - Awards and placement, 1971 (Box 25)
    - Bulletin-graduate, 1965-1968 (Box 25)
    - Classics Department, 1966-1967 (Box 25)
    - Commonwealth, 1968 (Box 25)
    - Consortium for Political Research, 1967-1968 (Box 25)
    - Cooperative Program in the Humanities, 1967-1968 (Box 25)
    - Courses-Colton, 1956 (Box 25)
    - Courses-Durden, 1956 (Box 25)
    - Courses-Ferguson, 1956 (Box 25)
    - Curtiss, John N.-miscellaneous, 1961 (Box 26)
    - Danforth Foundation, 1965-1969 (Box 26)
    - Deferred Admission due to the Draft (Selective Service), 1968 (Box 26)
    - Departmental Actions, 1960-1961 (Box 26)
    - Doctoral and MA Committees, 1960-1961 (Box 26)
    - Draft (Selective Service): cases, admission deferred, etc., 1967-1969 (Box 26)
    - Education Department-Master of Arts in Teaching, etc., 1966-1967 (Box 26)
    - Educational Testing Service-language and GRE, 1969 (Box 26)
    - Executive Committee of the Graduate Faculty, 1967 (Box 26)
    - Fellowships, prizes, etc., 1968-1969 (Box 26)
    - Fellowships for enrolled graduate students, 1966-1967 (Box 26)
    - Flyers-departmental, 1966-1969 (Box 26)
    - Foreign Students, 1966-1967 (Box 26)
    - General Correspondence, 1967-1969, 5 folders (Box 26)
    - Ginter, Donald-new course, Theory of Historical and Social Science Methodology, 1968-1969 (Box 26)
    - Graduate Awards, 1974 (Box 26)
    - Graduate Budget, 1972 (Box 26)
    - Graduate Committee, 1971 (Box 26)
    - Graduate School (description of jobs), 1973 (Box 26)
    - Graduate School-forms, procedures, etc., 1966-1969 (Box 26)
    - Graduate Students in History, 1955-1956 (Box 26)
    - Graduate Students (old and new) wanting jobs, 1969-1970 (Box 26)
    - Graduate Students-applications, 1961-1962 (Box 26)
    - Graduate Students-non-history, 1967 (Box 26)
    - Housing-graduate, undated (Box 26)
    - Inquiries (and responses), 1967-1969 (Box 26)
    - Interdisciplinary Program (forms), 1968 (Box 26)
    - Jobs, 1966 fall (Box 26)
    - Job Applicants, 1967-1969, 2 folders (Box 26)
    - Job Notices, 1971-1973 (Box 26)
    - Job Roster, 1970-1971 (Box 26)
    - Language Requirement, 1968-1969 (Box 26)
    - Latrobe, William T. papers, 1932-1975 (Box 26)
    - Loan Forms, undated (Box 26)
    - Mansergh, Nicholas, 1956 (Box 26)
    - Master of Arts in Teaching Program (MAT), 1953-1957, 3 folders (Box 26)
    - MAT-completed, 1954-1956 (Box 26)
    - May meeting of graduate staff, 1964-1969 (Box 26)
    - Minor Program-graduate, 1955 (Box 26)
    - Medieval History Program, 1967-1969 (Box 26)
    - Miscellaneous, 1958-1959 (Box 26)
    - National Defense Education Act (NDEA), 1967-1969 (Box 26)
    - National Defense Graduate Fellowship Applicants, 1961 (Box 26)
    - NDEA Title IV Fellowships, 1966-1967 (Box 26)
    - Newsletter (Curtiss), 1961 (Box 26)
    - Newsletter Information, 1968 (Box 26)
    - Newsletter Information, 1972 (Box 27)
    - Parker, (Dr. Harold), Curriculum Committee, 1967 (Box 27)
    - Phi Beta Kappa-graduate and honorary, 1967-1969 (Box 27)
    - Postdoctoral, undated (Box 27)
    - Preregistration, 1962-1967 (Box 27)
    - Publication Prize for PhDs, 1967 (Box 27)
    - Rapp, Dr. Marvin A., "The Importance of Remembering: Reflections and Reminiscences," 1971 (Box 27)
    - Registration, fall and spring, 1967-1968 (Box 27)
    - Research Triangle Awards, 1968 (Box 27)
    - Reports on Graduate Affairs, 1961, 1965-1966 (Box 27)
    - Research Assistance (inquiries), 1968 (Box 27)
    - Professor Ropp's Memo, Military History course, 1968 (Box 27)
    - Roster, 1966-1968 (Box 27)
    - Spengler, J.J., 1955 (Box 27)
    - Staff and letter to new Graduate Students, 1971 (Box 27)
    - Summer in Spain, 1970-1973 (Box 27)
    - Summer Session, 1956 (Box 27)
    - Southern Historical Association-Alumni Breakfast, 1967-1968 (Box 27)
    - Trinity College Historical Society, 1967-1969 (Box 27)
    - Undergraduate Information, 1967-1971 (Box 27)
    - Woodrow Wilson Fellowship, 1967-1968 (Box 27)
    - American Historical Association, membership and dissertation forms, 1983, undated (Box 27)
    - Course changes, undated (Box 27)
    - Course offering (approved forms), undated (Box 27)
    - Curriculum Vitae for job candidates, 1978-1979, undated (Box 27)
    - Financial Aid Applications (GAPSFAS), 1979-1980 (Box 27)
    - Foreign language used in term paper or project, undated (Box 27)
    - Graduate School research award applications, undated (Box 27)
    - Graduate Study Advisory Committee forms, 1980 (Box 27)